Hello everyone. I'm L Kesler. Um really
excited [music] for you all that you all
came here. Thank you. Um I hope to not
disappoint. Uh so this is a talk about
uh coding with Agentic AI, right? I want
to ask just a quick raise of hands. Have
anybody seen the first version of this
kind of fully on YouTube um like about
months ago? No cool. Um, some things
changed. I added a few things but yeah,
good. And then just to get the idea of
the audience like who codes with AI
daily?
Yay. Awesome. I think there's going to
be interesting things that we'll see
from my practice. So, I hope to have
some value. Uh, is there anybody who
feels like they're behind in coding with
AI and constantly like trying to catch
up, but like Yeah, thank you. Awesome.
All right, I think that's like we will
get you to awesome in the two hours. So,
let's do it. All right, let's start with
uh so let me share how it felt for me to
code with Agentic AI this year, right?
So,
Ken Beck has this amazing amazing
analogy that I absolutely adore uh of
the coding genie. And the Kodi genie is
not your genie from like the Aladdin um
Disney movies, right? This is the genie
from the books. It's the real thing and
the genie from the books is mischievous.
Um so
basically the coding with AI is like you
come to this genie and you're like, "Hey
Genie, I'd like some code please." And
Genie kind of pulls out the laptop, goes
to work, does some magic, and out come
working software.
Well, I mean, hopefully working
software, right? I mean, it often works
kind of. And then you look at it and it
shows you the diff and you're like, uh,
kind of looks good to me, I guess. So,
this is what it felt like to a developer
with 15 years experience to me this
year, this past year. And I guess your
experience may vary. I don't know if
you're all developers or if there are
any product managers. So if this your
product manager like that's like you
like look at it and you're like yeah and
like that's your life right you go to a
developer you wish for some software
outcomes something sometimes it works
sometime it doesn't
right but for a developer this is kind
of mind-blowing and it has been
mind-blowing to me so the question comes
to mind from this is how on earth do we
control this can we make it like because
I have a lot of frustration by kind of
doing this a lot this year so I
experimented a lot with
since November of the past year kind of
daily coding with it for day day and
night or evenings often times. So um so
I've been exploring it and trying to
understand what is in front of us and so
first of all what can we even control
here? It will be good to understand what
we can control if we were to kind of
control the genie right. So first of all
we're developer we're here and there's
some foundation model somewhere right so
this is the llms um chpt I don't know
oppus from cloud and so on and um they
kind of need to talk to each other right
would be good to to be able to talk so
before it was browsers this year it's
became agendic
right so we have this new thing which is
agendic coding tool and they can be
different some some of them some of them
pretend to be ID my favorite ones don't.
Um, and kind of the things we have here,
we can choose this level, right? We can
choose the coding tool and we can kind
of sometimes choose the model that comes
with it or sometimes they are kind of
coupled
and then on the agenda coding tool level
we can configure it. So it kind of AI
you can think about as AI comes with
default configurations that are often
not helpful and we'll see uh how we can
change some things with them and then we
can also give it tools which makes it
more powerful and information and then
as a developer you can navigate so you
can go there don't do that a lot of
don't do that and then automate right so
we can make some things easier for us so
this is basically like what we have
control over right so what do we do with
this So this is what we're going to go
through. If your feeling is terror when
you look at this, that's as normal. Like
that's the first reaction. Nobody
reports terror at the end of the talk.
So I think you're good. And I'm going to
walk you through this and we're going to
like take this very like step by step.
So don't worry. I got you. Really, what
it is is three tracks. So imagine this
is a hike, right? Through patterns. So
I'm talking like walking you with you
through patterns. First patterns are
about context management. This is the
basics of everything, right? So how do
we and and and then you you you're going
to start thinking about quality and
reliability. How can we make it less
crazy? And then communication. How do we
talk to it such such that we make
ourselves more efficient? All right. And
that's going to be two pizzas of five
minutes where you're welcome to ask
questions. Ideally, if you can, please
hold your questions till then. Uh if you
really really need to ask ask, go away.
Go ahead. Right. So okay. So this is
resources. you might want to pull it if
if you're interested. Uh basically 32
patterns um a little bit more than my
first version cuz somebody pointed out
that I am not talking to about
reliability as much as I wanted to. And
um so the resources the resources have a
map so you can kind of pull it up and
I'm going to be naming the patterns as I
go like and numbering them so you can
kind of keep track of where you are
right and kind of pit stops also I think
should help. All right. So,
uh, hope everyone got this. So, all
right. Let's start. So, first of all,
context management. The core problem
that is going to you're going to see
throughout no matter what in all tools
is that LM cannot learn from you, right?
So, the model has fixed weights and it
is stateless. So, what do I mean by
stateless? So really the memory you get
even in like browser and stuff is a lie.
It's a
an attempt to save you from a really bad
user experience because if you talk to a
real model or like an API, right? If you
go down to the level of API and start
talking to LLMs directly, this is your
experience.
You come to it and ask a simple
question, it answers it. Then you like
ask a follow-up question that kind of
implies, right, what is it in
Portuguese? Uh, so you kind of need to
know this part. And the eye is like
what's what?
Because really like it only sees this
last message, right? So every tool that
you're dealing with implements a memory
layer and
kind of when if you if they don't like
you would be like yeah not a very good
user experience, right? So how is it
memory layer works? Right? So basically
there's a concept of context window that
every everything introduces, right? And
that context window is something we need
to know how it works really well and
that's going to help us and make us
really powerful. So uh what experience
with context window looks like is this
basically again you go to the genie and
you're like hey what's 2 plus2
um that thing goes into context window
initially the context window is empty
then this is put in and that's what's
sent to the genie the context window
right the context of the context window
then genie looks at it well it's a
simple question four okay you ask your
followup again now what happens is all
the three messages come in and including
the genuine including that own
also tools. Anything in the tools is
kind of spawning there, but it's
invisible to you. So, it like it might
actually bite you. Um, and because the
genie kind of looks at it and sees all
three things, it can actually reply to
you eloquently,
right? So, this is your new prompt. Like
your prompt is not what you think it is.
It's the whole context window, the whole
conversation. And it goes and like,
yeah, still four, right? Portuguese. um
math doesn't change much. Okay, so
basically this is by the end of this
conversation. This is a context window.
This is what is is inside a context
window, right? And it's you can think
about it as a string you're always
concatenating with. And some like some
tools you're using kind of hack it a
bit. So like allow you to roll back, but
like in in the row form that's that's
what everything is how it works inside,
right? So we have this context window
and the we only have two operations that
we can do with it really, right? So we
can start a conversation right or we can
append to it. So we can kind of append
to like by sending messages by doing
something or you can reset start a new
conversation right. So this is our like
this is what we're dealing with when
we're managing context and um the next
thing you need to understand here is
basically there's a concept of context
rout. So the context window is not
universal. The context degrades as the
conversation progresses. LM and and the
way it manifests is LM stops following
kind of more and more of things you told
it before and that happens long long
before the context window limit because
some some people are like oh we're going
to get like now it's like 4 the new clot
has like 1 million talking window. Yeah,
but like your to your context is this.
So you can think about this is not in
scale but roughly like the context
window is really really good when you
open the new conversation and so like
you kind of start
in really good good state it's behaving
and following instructions and it starts
dropping like suddenly it stops
following the everything you told it and
then it just plummets to ground right so
um
what it means is this basically the AI
cannot pattern and there's context rod
and that means we need to manage
context, right? We can't just put things
in there and not think about it. So
that's pattern number one, context
management. And how do we manage
context? So this is like the simplest
thing you can think of like you're
dealing with something ephemeral. Well,
maybe uh let's put it into a file and
that way it's not ephemeral, right? So
knowledge document is that first pattern
uh to of managing context and this is
actually surprisingly simple and
surprisingly effective. People who have
been using them effectively are
reporting like much more efficiently the
teams. So the idea is like that simple.
So on the left there is this context
window right this is um our conversation
and this is like the all kind of stuff
you put in there and there's this uh
green golden pieces or green pieces that
you really really care about. you taught
AI something. You told it things. You
put energy in there and you wasted your
time on it. So kind of you right now
you're at the end of this and you're
kind of like, oh, I have to reexlain
this stuff again, right? Um that's kind
of annoying. It would be really lovely
if we could do this. Give me a new
context with all the goodness, right?
And take away all the garbage. So
basically this first pattern of
knowledge document allows you to do this
deadly simple idea. grab your stuff and
put it into a file. Right now you can
point to it and the effort of you
pointing to it versus reiterating
yourself is kind of makes a lot of
difference. I was so annoyed at first by
having to reiterate myself a lot gets
old very quickly. All right. So then um
now it's easier to hit reset. Now I can
open the new conversation. I can have
things I can point to immediately.
Right. All right. So basically we start
with knowledge. We have a knowledge
document and a clean context. And after
you reset, you're like, "Hey, load
important things." And now you have the
good stuff in there, right? Very simple.
All right. So, ground rules.
This is so important. Then some systems
or I guess since about April, every
everything started implementing this.
There's ground rules, right? And the
idea of ground rules is there's some
things that you really really care about
that you want to be loaded always so you
don't have to actually pull it in. It
saves you energy, right? So for example,
like what do you care about? If you are
hiking like always put away fire or
people will die and so on bad, right? So
this kind of stuff but in coding so and
there's different implementations of
this right so there's agents MD that's
kind of becoming a standard a new
standard there's clot code like has
cloud MD and so on. So they all kind of
implement this nowadays and they are
different
uh so they're on two different levels.
First of all, every everywhere on your
computer, right? That's the user level
one. So no matter where you open your
favorite IDE or coding editor, you have
them or in the project level and context
there is a bit different but like the
project level is like what is important
in your project. The core things and you
need to be very careful about what you
put in there. Uh because we we'll we'll
see why in additional in addition to
this but the core thing to understand
here is this stuff is always on your
context. You don't need to do anything
about it. You see how you open it and
it's there. All right. So, how do we get
to knowledge documents? There's an easy
easy technique that's called extract
knowledge. Um, so what's going on is
this. Basically, you have this dirty
context and a genie. You put in all this
work that I mentioned before and but
it's really hard to for you to get to
it. I mean, you could, right? But it's
work. So, what you can do is basically
like, hey genies, hit hit save for me,
right? and it pulls it into a file and
you point it to a file and saves it
there. There's a little bit more to this
because like the zoom levels come into
play. Sometimes it generalizes too much.
So you can actually like um do do things
like think about how you you don't want
it too generalized. So I'll show you
later uh how you can make make the
documents more manageable. But that's a
general idea. Very simple, right? But so
whenever you put some effort into a
conversation, it's a fleeting thing.
take it out, put it into a file. Now you
have something that you can use, right?
Uh and you can kind of create and you
can modify the same way if you edit
something same thing. All right, next
question. Can we put everything in one
file?
Well, first of all, it probably won't
fit unless you don't have many things to
care about in life, right? So the
context window is limited and first in
first out. So the oldest stuff gets
erased and then everything is competing
for that space. So uh what it looks like
I probably everybody knows this but I
just to make sure every everybody is
aware let's pretend we have a tiny
context window just like four lines
right so same conversation we have the
same conversation uh we're kind of
populating it here so it goes here and
now we're kind of out of space so what
what happens here what happens here
depend on the tool you're dealing with
right so first of all uh things need to
kind of fit in so most pe most things
try to put it in not always but most of
them and what do you do with this old
stuff, right? So, sever several things
may happen. First of all, it may get
dropped. Um, things like Windsurf, I'm
not sure what they're doing nowadays,
but like in April they were doing that.
They're just dropping and this thing
gets out of your context and you don't
know that it's out of your context,
which is interesting. There's ways to
notice it. I'll I'll show you later. And
then um whole conversations get
compressed. That's cloud code way,
right? They they thankfully tell you.
So, like grab the whole conversation,
give it to AI. Hey, I shortened it up
and now they start a new conversation
with that summary. Not the same thing as
your old context by any means, but like
at least you don't have to reexlain
yourself. Kind of nice. And then
especially on AI level and also chat GBT
in the browser and stuff like that are
just erroring out. Hey, start a new
conversation. Too much stuff, right? Um,
so another problem with the context
window is this. And I didn't realize how
much of the problem this is. And also I
think that many people who are actually
coding with AI a lot also don't realize
this because if I didn't see this I
wouldn't know. So let me show you. So
basically I have this ground rules. So I
have in my codemd I have a couple of
rules about productivity and honesty. So
this is kind of the first one is from
Elizabeth Hendrickson. Really like it.
Um tell me something I need to know and
if I if even if I don't want to hear it
whenever I talk to you and really kind
of want a better feedback than this is
awesome. Um, I I do that, right? And
then I kind of took it further and I'm
like, well, what if we also proactive
proactively warn me if I'm about to make
a mistake? That would be nice, right?
So, I put it in and I was waiting for it
to hit and I was waiting for a long
time.
So, I was using this clot code and you I
was doing all kinds of things in it and
one of the things I did in it is commit.
So, it coded, it tested, did other stuff
and I committed too. It commits pretty
nicely. I liked it. Um, and what I was
dealing with is this generalist um,
agent. So like you can think about this
as a context and there's all kinds of
things there like some things I pulled
from other places and say this is my
commit roles, right? So they're there.
So actually um, there's a difference
between the left side and the right
side. a specialist agent even if you so
not always but like even if you have the
same size context but that that one is
just committer the behavior is going to
be dramatically different and I didn't
realize it because um so
basically I started committing in a
separate window right and then suddenly
an interesting thing happened and
basically that leads to lump has limited
focus so let me show you focus stations
right So
uh now I have a main clot code and I
have a little committer. So the
committer is like there just sitting
there and just comm I'm committing in
that window. The only thing I like I
told it how I like my commits and I'm
just pressing C commit. Awesome. It
looks at the if. Okay, this looks fine.
And both of them are pointing at my
ground rules that I just showed you. Be
proactive. Warn me when I'm about to
mess up. Right. And the left side never
did
the the the this one. But suddenly my
committer does this and when I saw it
the first time I almost fell out the
chair. Suddenly my committer like it was
committing committing committing and
then suddenly hey ladder you're about to
commit your non models. Did you mean to
do that? I mean that's there's ways to
like actually there's reasons to do that
sometimes but actually no I didn't mean
to do this in this case. Thanks. That's
actually very helpful. Right. And then
well your docs here you're kind of
violating your own like rules about um
like how to do um how to name the files.
didn't you didn't mean to do that? I'm
like, no, no, thank you. So helpful.
Right? And then there's there's all
kinds of weirdness that it it pointed
out. So like this PDF file is like, did
you mean like does it need to be
committed or not? I'm not sure what to
do with this. Right? So this level of
productivity was unheard of from the
like the main the main window that I was
coding in. So what we're dealing with
here is a specialist. And this is my
term. This is also sorry. This is my
term. This is no in no means like a
everybody's term but I think many people
don't realize uh how good and what the
difference is right the difference here
is between never and always.
It's kind of nuts. All right. So kind of
narrow scope means way way better
instruction following. So I often code
right now in many many windows. I'm
mostly limited by monitor. Um so
basically what that means is anything
you put in your context that is not
being followed is actively harmful.
So when you shove like always do this
always do that if you ignored like
that's actually making things worse. Um
and that brings us to references. So um
that means we kind of need to granularly
control the context and be able to pull
in things when we need it only the
things we care about. So we talked about
ground rules. Those are the things are
always in your context. This is
something you really care about
everywhere no matter what. So my
productivity rules I really want my
agent to be proactive please that is
really helpful right and then there's
other things though that you care about.
So for example maps in the repository
right so this file is over there um test
sh is here please run the test sh not
the node something something right. Um
and then there's guides right so code
style for example please follow this
code style. Um then there's playbooks uh
for example TDD process um like so
process files by wall and falco have
some I have a video in my resources if
you're not familiar with process files
they're really good really great and
then to-do lists um like here's the task
please follow to implement and then
scratch pads are helpful temporary
documentation that you just get rid of.
So all of that is kind of something that
you may want, right? And the ground
rules are always on, but this thing is
pulled in as needed because you want
this granular control of everything. So
the way it works looks like this.
Basically, you open your context window.
Ground rules are here already, right?
Um, and now you start coding and you
start filling the context with stuff.
You code with it and so on. And now
you're like, um, I'd like James Shore
nullables, please. So I have a file
where I teach AI how to do nullables.
Well, makes a lot of difference. It has
James Shores examples. Um, so I pull it
in by reference. I use slash commands in
clot code for that. So it's a it's a
second thing for me to grab it, right? I
just slashnullables is what I do. And
then I code again. I do some nullable
stuff and then I need something else. I
need TDD process. I pull it in as I need
it and then continue on and then test
plan. Same thing, right? So you kind of
start to build this knowledge library
that you have of things you kind of use
the most often and the conversation the
next time will look nothing else nothing
like this right because the only only
part that will be the same is ground
rules but that allows you that narrow
narrow control over your context um and
we just spoke about why that's important
and then the next question right again
uh how do we decide what goes where what
files gets what so very simple I I
suggest this. So say you have a context
window on the left and you have a
project MD on the right and you put
everything in your project MD like your
front end test plan, back end test plan,
style guide, Python stuff, project info,
everything's there, right? Uh what are
the problem with that right? So say I
start coding and now I need that and I
only need this front end test plan from
that right there's no m way for me to
just point to that sadly. So now I have
to pull it in fully. All right. And
there's noise, right? And we we talked
about like distracting stuff is badness.
It actually harms the way you the
results you get, right? So you can't
peel pull out individual pieces. So
knowledge composition is the pattern
that basically allows like just think
about things you need to pull in. So if
I split them out this way, right, I can
now just pull in front end test plan and
like all the rest is not is not um
polluting my context. All right. So we
talked about can it learn and context
rot. So we need to manage context. We
can't just thoughtlessly put things in.
And then there's a knowledge document
pattern that is like the basics of the
basics of how to manage context.
Simplest thing. Uh then the ground rules
are basically things that always in your
context. Those are the knowledge
documents that are always pul pulled in
and you can extract knowledge
deliberately so you're not wasting
effort and time put in into that
fleeting conversation you're having. And
then so there's a limited context window
and limited focus means that agents get
distracted
right and um focused agent is just
magical when you experience it the first
time especially and then reference docs
and knowledge composition is basically
how you get control of your context more
granular control so um let's get to um a
little bit more and then we're going to
have a fivem minute break where we have
questions so I think I forgot to tell
you so three tracks there's going to be
two breaks in between and you can ask me
questions, right? All right. So, um
another problem is this AI is really
noisy by default. So, whenever you ask
AI any question, you see it usually
gives you a giant page, right? Uh so,
you have to fight that and the actually
that is actively harmful as soon as you
start extracting knowledge into
documents that that verbosity act
actively harms you. So, you have to
fight it. And
um so here's an example of noisiness,
right? So I started learning Rust and I
was like, "Hey,
um I I asked my to set up the the Rust
project for me. It lovely did a lovely
job of that. Okay. And now I look at
this cargo tom file. I'm like, hm, what
is it? I'm curious. Tell me more about
this." And now it gives me this.
And when I look at it, I'm like, well, I
don't care about this stuff yet. Don't
care about that. I don't care about
that. I really, really don't care about
this detail, right? Doesn't matter. So
then the next thing I do always pretty
much is much more succinct please like I
probably should make a slash command for
that. Um so and what it gives me uh when
I say that is this. So check it out. So
cargo is a Ras project configuration
file. Oh like package JSON I I get it.
Okay. And okay it has project metadata
dependency builds things. Oh and you
can't build without it. Oh okay I
understand. Now I have an idea. Notice
how the level of detail here matches the
level of my curiosity and this is just
noise,
right? So what we're dealing with here
is um this is pattern number nine,
semantic zoom. So basically nowadays you
can zoom in and out of text. This wasn't
a thing two years back, right? And the
way you zoom in is you ask questions.
You're like, "Hey, tell me more about
this or what do you mean by X? How do
you write something?" like ask for more
detail and AI will give you especially
if it has more stuff otherwise it will
come up with its own imagin imagine
things or start looking around but like
if you have if you're asking a thing
about a a code then it can go deeper
right and you can zoom in and then
zooming out is like make it shorter make
it more succinct tlddr high level right
so the zooming in deepens understanding
when you want to deepen understanding
And the zooming out is making things
manageable with the eye because it will
overload you. It is a crazy talking
machine and so many people allow it to
overload them and I'm like I don't think
it's helpful. I don't think it's
necessary as well. You don't have to
suffer. So basically this goes to my
default like ground rules
talk to me really succinctly, right? And
that makes a lot of difference. So you
have to actually so this leads to
pattern number 10 noise cancellation. So
you have to actually uh actively manage
the noise, right? So I said like so you
force consistentness in knowledge
documents that's especially powerful in
knowledge documents. So as soon as you
start extracting knowledge, you'll see
how much dead dead text rights like dead
code. AI absolutely produces that code.
Um but like in knowledge documents it
just starts like oh I read this thing I
edited that part but like this thing is
kind of I needed to update it but I
didn't think about updating it.
especially if the thing grows and that
becomes crazy and unmanageable very
quickly. It's really annoying. That's
actually making the patterns of all the
knowledge documents hard to manage. So
what really really helps is okay uh look
at the code look at the document
make sure that the they match right
everything is updated but also zoom out
really hard like really far and the
previous clouds do did it very well. the
newest the newest one, the 4.5 one
actually is much more noisy than I like.
So I kind of have to fight with it a bit
more. But the original claude like I was
really happy to see when I saw Claude MD
for the first time because it was
zooming out the same way as I was was
zooming out earlier on and I think it
makes a lot of difference right and you
can do the same in responses to you. So
whenever AI gives you a giant page like
much more succinctly, right? And then
you see the gists and it's so much more
scannable and you're not overloaded with
details.
I also also think about this part of
delete more closely, right? So don't
allow this is token machine. Don't like
it's really we all have this habit of oh
what if they need it like especially if
you have several people in the in the
repo, right? Oh, I'm afraid to touch it
and so on. Like if you have several
people with noisy eyes, you have to kind
of embrace deleting, right? So, G is
your friend. Uh, just delete the stuff
you don't need. Don't let clutter leave.
And, um, I also like temporary throwaway
docs. So, I deliberately create some
docs that I know will going to die soon.
So, like like todos and so on. So, I can
delete them u without mercy. And so,
zoom levels seem simple, but actually
you can take them super far. And I'm I
think I'm still kind of figuring that
out. And it's really really interesting.
So first of all the first thing I do
with this is like I go to repos and I
poke at it right like hey show me the
architecture and I really I I like ask
you for this. So I think I bet somebody
will be like oh it's also great at
mermaid. Yeah I know it's great at
mermaid but like mermaid takes me away
so I have to open something and here I'm
like in in the context I AI is really
good at producing asy and I am decent at
looking at it and editing it. So it's a
lightweight way of poke at things. Ask
questions and get quick answers on any
Zoom level you care about. I can go
deeper and ask for more diagrams or more
succinct information. Right? Really
really quick way to start learning
something because previously you have to
go drop down into the level of the
detail the code is written on. Right? So
entry points and all that that's kind of
taxing that takes away this load and
that's super helpful. All right. Um, so
like I said, prevent AI from overloading
you. That makes docs manageable. You can
use the this semantic zoom to get
answers to questions much faster. And
it's really powerful in tests. So in my
resources, I have a talk with Lan Lan
Falco and we kind of show how you can
zoom out in text in tests. So when you
open a test file, especially written by
AI, but not not necessarily.
>> All right.
All right. I hope that's the only table
it's going to fall.
All right. So, um, so in test, so I have
a talk with Llewellen about zooming out
in tests. And when you open a test file,
it's really hard to tell unless you
really really care and put a lot of
effort into it, what you're testing and
what you're missing, right? It's really
hard to tell in a glance, what am I
testing here? What's missing? because
you have to read all of this stuff. So
you can zoom out of text tests
deliberately and this talk kind of shows
you how that's one of the ways. Approval
test is one of the ways to do that and
you can do pretty graphic like you can
especially if you're dealing with
something like I don't know that has UI
right or APIs are pretty great for that
as well like on on that talk I have an
example of API how we made the whole uh
kind of ugly Java test suite into a kind
of manageable documentation. We kind of
reinvented um EDDD there, but that's a
good example of that. And then you can
do high level debugging, which is kind
of nuts the first thing I saw it. So I
sometimes wipe code
uh sometimes and I often usually just
refactor after, but still. So when you
wipe code and UI gets stuck,
how do you debug? Right? And I found a
way that works really well. Uh because I
don't want to drop down to the code
level and like run debugger for reals,
right? what you can do is zoom out and
you say hey here's a code piece like AI
is like yeah it's working it's fine and
it's not working you're like okay
explain me the code in English right and
usually dev speaks to you and but you
start seeing things that immediately pop
up that are nonsense for example the
first thing I saw was like oh it's
creating a repository every on every
call well that's dumb let's not do that
okay refactored now I see the next thing
because it's not like you know in my
face that that horribleness it's Now I
can see the next thing. Oh, okay.
Interesting. This thing over there, tell
me more, right? And it actually often
times understands itself. So this is
like high level debugging like vibe
debugging or something. Uh that's kind
of interesting. And you can do much more
with this. Like I have some things that
I'm doing with refactoring that is
interesting, but it's not ready to show
yet. Uh so all right. So
uh basically semantic zoom is is a new
thing. It's really really powerful. I
think you can take it much further than
than what we understand about it right
now. And then noise cancellation is
going to save your brains. And
especially if you have three like many
developers in in in the repo, use that.
It's going to really be really helpful.
And that brings us to first pit stop. So
we have about five minutes. Do you have
any questions? We can talk about it.
>> One second. Let's do the microphone. I
think it's going to help everyone.
when you generated the knowledge
documents to keep in the uh context
window. I guess you use AI to do that.
>> You don't have to. You don't have to. I
do a lot because this is an easy way to
get information out.
>> Exactly. So that's my question. Uh what
is your experience with that like
percentage wise? most of the time will
get you the the information that you
want to keep or do you have any tricks
to make sure you get the information you
>> zoom levels is the trick
>> okay
>> and also look at it and if you don't
like it tell it and but zooming out like
does so much goodness it's just nuts
because I I often see that details are
details do interesting things sometimes
when you add examples so I have this
James Shore example like nullables I
mentioned right they're amazing thing if
you don't know the the skill by the way
look it up um so What the way I I
created it is basically this. James
Shore has an amazing article about how
to do nullables. It's by James Shore. It
has James Shaw examples. The goodness,
right? So I point at this and and be
like, "Okay, zoom it out, get rid of
text, leave the leave the examples. Now
I have a file. I can it's a reference
document. So I can point to it and and
grab it and and teach AI how to do
nables well at a at a fingertip, right?
Very quickly. So um so this level of uh
so the way I zoomed out was kind of
helpful there. Um I'm sorry I'm I'm
spacing out about the question. Can you
repeat the question?
>> No I think you answered is whether the
question was if you find that using AI
and with the specific um uh tricks that
you talk about you get most of the time
what you want.
>> Right. Right. Right. Right. The
problems. Yes. That's what I was trying
to Thank you. So the problem is this um
sometimes when you specify when you zoom
when you extract knowledge and you get
the the examples and you then you you
kind of exper you expect when you give
it to another AI it will work the same
way but it doesn't work the same way as
a context. What I found was those
examples sometimes make AI over focus on
those so it kind of starts applying them
where they don't apply. So zooming out
and say don't bring this detail in
actually helps but you have to play with
it and you have to test. So if you want
a reliable way to be like I extracted
knowledge does it work open a new window
pull it in play and test and
[clears throat] if you don't like it you
still have that old context and you can
kind of extract it also helps to saves
context so I clot has actually a way to
so cloud code has a basically everything
is in your project directory but they
delete it in 30 days so I have it in in
the was it called git yeah right
>> in g so and the second part is did you
play with shared memory claude started I
think recently shared memory across uh
chats across um and does this knowledge
extraction by themselves. You don't have
any more control over the content of
that. Did you play with that?
>> Did you mean the cloud one, not claw
cloud code one? The one that I
introduced with uh I forgot what it's
called. Do you remember what it's
called?
>> Uh the the the configuration that I see
is shared memory. turn it on or off
across your project, across your chats,
across your
>> I would basically treat it the same way
I treat my ground rules and with the
same care. So I I don't I don't play
with that myself.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No,
>> I I'll try to see if the rules
>> I think maybe we're talking clot code
versus cloud and that's a different
thing. This have skills. They're pretty
wonderful. I think they're pretty
wonderful. Like I think that was my
knowledge knowledge because I I did this
talk and then I saw that and I think
this is my knowledge documents
>> pretty much or the reference docs. Mhm.
>> For the succinctness,
do you put that in your ground rules or
do you like the granular level control
like in the chat?
>> No, because I want zoomed out everywhere
because it's so noisy. I because it's
overwhelms me everywhere. So zoomed out
all the way. Ground rules.
So, especially when projects get really
really big and you have really really
big teams working on them, you you kind
of want to share all of these knowledge
documents across it.
>> Yep.
>> How have you gone about structuring that
in an effective way? Yep.
>> So that search all of a sudden doesn't
become the problem that you're solving
ultimately in order to construct that
context window.
>> That's a great question. I think it
depends what it is, right? So, first of
all, like you probably want your own
personal ones. Those are probably your
owns. Um I do tend to so my stuff I have
some things that are pulling in from
different places and it's a bit I just
just keep it on git and make sure that
they're there for the team. Uh I think
put them in the repo of the team. Um you
can also be like have a project that has
all the ones that are commonly shared
across that right across the team. So if
you have other projects, so basically
it's tricky because you have to allow AI
to see that from a different project and
sometimes permissions get tricky, but um
yeah, I don't know if you guys are
living dangerously. I am and I probably
shouldn't. Um yeah,
but yeah, this roughly what I would do,
I think, but I think this this so people
are trying to do databases and so on. I
personally don't do that because I don't
know about you guys, I feel this world
is is kind of the last year is kind of
crazy because it feels like everything
is so lightweight and I want control and
I I value that control at the
fingertips. If I have ground rules, I
want to go there edit it immediately and
I don't want a database inside it
because it feels like a block. So I tend
to not do that. I don't know that it's
like I also don't have a giant team
right now like I used to like man like
be a team lead for a big team. Uh I
don't do this anymore right now. So I
kind of a little bit more isolated than
that if I had so I don't have a good
advice for this giant team and like all
that stuff. So maybe I'll just
>> uh thank you for saying that. I
generally agree that like um the agents
you have to teach them about the
database then and it's like a task that
you don't want have to do. So, keeping
things in the repository is good. Um,
we've been working on a CLI that uh just
has like a JSON object that associates
like specific implementation files with
documentation files and wondering like
so that we could get to a like um a
concept of code of documentation
coverage and wondering if you had any
thoughts on that.
>> Nice. I wouldn't do JSON because JSON is
I don't know have you seen this thing?
So, people are evaluating like the token
usage of JSON versus um just plain CSV
and the difference is kind of madness.
Uh, it's pretty big, so I'd probably do
something else. But the idea is solid. I
think I I call them maps. Basically, I'm
like, "Okay, here's a map. Here's
everything you need to know about it."
And I usually include it in CloudMD.
And then like the AI doesn't need to
search every time, right?
>> Yes. But I was going to say um then you
can uh add it to your pre-commit so that
like it
>> Oh, that's amazing. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Absolutely love that. I I wish I
had more
time to experiment with that. I I really
want to kind of try to do that. the so
the idea of like keeping docs up to date
with the code right that's that's
crucial I think I don't know a good way
to solve it I really I'm really curious
>> the library that we have
>> would love to thanks
>> awesome all right
>> yeah I think that was similar at the
ending there how do you keep your what
you're doing as you keep developing and
everything keep changing there's just
more and more and more markdown files
everywhere
>> yeah unsolved problem to me for now
unfortunately I think people are trying
to actively solve all that. Uh I have
thoughts about it, but I think we're
going to too deep too deep of it to go
there. But yes, thank you. I wish I had
a better solution.
>> All right, let's take that one and let's
continue on because I'm a bit worried
about time after that.
>> Yes, my question is related to
documentation that is created more
intended like for humans. Do you have
the problem of duplicating u
documentation where one is intended
maybe for a developer and the other one
is intended for the AI or how do you
manage that situation? I guess uh the
ground rules are kind of kind of sort of
for AI, right? That's the thing. For the
rest of it, I tend to just have uh
things for both. So I can it doesn't
matter much. I find that documentation
helps both AIS and humans quite a lot.
So I don't know that I have I don't I
don't discriminate. I guess
>> isn't discrimination. I'm not sure.
[laughter]
Right. So all right. So let's continue
on if that's okay. Right. We can I have
another pit stop. So I have another and
we've we're trying not to run out of
time. So let's go. So another another
kind of walk through of another problem
is nondeterminism. How do you make it
more reliable and quality wise, right?
So all right. So first pattern that
helps me at least a lot is knowledge
checkpoint. So and the idea is like make
it really easy to roll back. So let's
think about this. So we have we have
we're coding with AI, right? So we
planned a feature uh like it took maybe
30 minutes to plan that feature and now
we're ready and now you you you tell AI
to implement oftent times it just runs
off and tries to implement even before
you tell it tell it to actually yeah I'm
ready um especially claude and then it
potentially fails right and then so the
problem here is like now you have to
start from scratch right and some tools
kind of make it easier for you right
this roll back stuff but in general what
you can do ac that will work across
everything is uh well
your scattered knowledge over here right
um and getting to the state the same
state is a bit problematic so what you
can do is basically introduce a safe
point before you implement very easy
right and the way you save point is
basically save it into a file so you
plan with AI the next step before you
implement hey AI we just had a lovely
conversation we'll be we're ashamed to
lose it please save it into a file right
and then you commit
And after that AI goes and implements.
So you have a knowledge checkpoint. AI
goes and implements. But you protected
your time during planning, right? This
is the most important time that I don't
want to lose. And it makes it easy to
roll back. So now like okay, I have to
roll back. Fine. I'm going to pull in
the file and start again because you
know nondeterminism. So retry actually
makes makes it work or you can tweak it
because you learned something, right? So
it takes you very very little time. So
here's an example from hack for good. So
there was a hackathon this summer on
agile 2025
um like we did it's really really fun
interesting story but like so we um
implemented in three days um a thing for
nonprofit and so this is an example of
one one of the the knowledge share point
there right so we already have a file on
the right so we have this file and this
is like what the project is it's a
simple counter and now we want to add a
keyboard support right uh I don't just
go and like hey add keyboard support I
go and say save save that information we
plan into it to a file and now I have a
knowledge checkpoint this is simple but
your other stuff won't be simple and it
helps because you if you get into a
habit of that when you are in a
complicated situation you you'll have
the habit right so it'll make a
difference and often times AI run off
and do things so I have to basically be
like so in in this case I was like let
me see
yeah so I had to interrupt it before it
runs off and be like no no no no no
please save it into a file so you're
going to face that especially claude is
super eager in things right and one
thing it enables so parallel
implementations is probably thing many
people are familiar with so it's not
going to be news to many people maybe uh
but so the idea is simple but that
knowledge checkpoint actually helps with
this pattern so uh the idea is like okay
you're dealing with something that
nondeterministic so it's rolling like
rolling a dice well what if you cared
about three a
But you so but like if you roll a dice
the chance of getting a three is one one
six right? So okay uh what if you roll
it more times right and you can do it
with AI and um here's how to use
knowledge checkpoint. So basically
because you already have this knowledge
checkpoint right and now it's easy to
roll back. So what you can do is so this
is an example of me like showing how I
code with AI to to a to a new developer
um like a intern and so we took a
ricochet robot game and implemented it
and this is the implementation that
didn't work but thing is this is not the
only implementation I did so basically
you I have I have planned with AI I
saved this into project MD and todo MD
now I have a knowledge checkpoint and
now I can branch out from that right so
g trees basically are a hacky way. It's
an old old feature from Git that wasn't
used before agents I think much and the
way they're doing it they're just
basically creating clones of the whole
repo in a separate folder and the way
for git to see them that's all it is
right so now you actually can go into
each of those branches and start an
agent there and so this is g work trace
and now you have three genies working
for you or 10 if you would like right
and the the things you can do with this
is twofold first of all well you're
dealing with something nondeterministic
if you really want it to work you
content peril and like this for example
failed but this two worked so you can be
like okay and now the next trick is you
you can you can choose and pick pieces
and I especially like it for front ends
so whenever you're you're writing a
front end especially with CL clot is
pretty great at front ends but I often
like if you roll the dice it will be a
different front end every time even if
like you give it the same document right
but you'll notice that you like this
piece here that piece there that piece
over there oh layout is great color
scheme is
With AI, you can actually grab things
from different places, combine, and then
you get a richer interface. So, I like
kind of rolling the dice deliberately
and using that. So, you're kind of
weaponizing the non nondeterminism here.
And so, this is an example for this. So,
I rolled the dice three times. The
center thing was the the one I showed
you. That's kind of bad. Doesn't even
move. Problematic. Uh, so I don't like
anything about this one. But the left
side actually moved pretty well. So,
that was that was decent. And it had
walls that I didn't hate. And then so
this is a row but it just runs into
lines and you need to put it into a
square of a certain color, right? And
but this one actually has arrows that I
like. So I combine the three and now I
have a thing that I actually like that
actually works as well. So just I mean
this is VI coding like playing with it,
right? This not but you can also use
this in a project if you're careful and
thoughtful and kind of
you can find ways to use it for good.
All right, the next thing. So okay,
nondeterminism. So we're dealing with
something nondeterministic.
So the idea is uh pattern 13 of load of
low determinism. So here's an example.
So again this is from hack for good. Uh
if you want to see the app you can. So
this is basically a simple counter on
the left. We we needed to be able so we
were in the room. We were releasing like
mad three days in a row and we wanted
people when they come into the room to
be able to to see the app immediately.
Right? So we have a screen like this and
on it a thing like that you're seeing in
front of you. So people can pull in the
phone and like okay and I try play with
the app. Okay. So how do we create this?
Right. Nothing hard. So the thing we
could do is uh and we didn't do is take
a screenshot of the current page using
puppeteer MCP because that's not
repeatable, right? That's unreliable.
Because if next time when I'm super
rushed, the last thing I want to do is
deal with stupid AI that doesn't
suddenly work, right? Three three days
my own schedule trying to do goodness
here. Okay, so what do you do here? So
what you do is like write so AI is
amazing at writing tools. It is just
wonderful and it can write tools for
itself. So here I'm asking write me a
script for for capturing a screenshot,
right? And goes away. It messes with
puppeteer. It doesn't work, but it's
really good at figuring things out. So,
it does. And suddenly, I have a script.
So, I created a tool, right? And the
tool is just as simple as this. I can
run it if I want to. And it's always
going to be deterministic, but I use
nondeterministic thing to get to
deterministic, right? So, it's squeezing
nondeterminist out of my system. And uh
AI can do this as well, right? And I can
now use it as a tool inside process
files inside another process. So, I can
combine this and use it. So really
really powerful. All right. So we talked
about nondeterminism how it's a thing
with AI and knowledge checkpoint is like
a simple simple way to kind of save
state before you implement and save your
time. This parallel implementations that
that knowledge checkpoint allows and
enables. It doesn't have to be you don't
have to do it for parallel
implementation but it's helping because
you can add another one so easy. It's so
easy to add more if you want to. And
then you offload deterministic. So
anything that can be deterministic
should probably be deterministic. Script
everything. Don't AI is not good at
determinism. So don't use it for that.
Right? All right. So another problem. So
many people who are starting with AI are
like AI hallucinates. That's a big
problem, right? Well,
so code is self-verifiable. So that's
the one exception, right? So the
knowledge is a different, right? So like
what's the the capital of I don't know
England, right? Um that could be
potentially a lie. But like it's very
easy to test code. You can just run it.
So if you didn't like if you are
complaining about getting something that
doesn't work from AI because you didn't
run it, maybe that's on you.
But what what I found is um many times
when people are complaining about
hallucinations, it really really helps
to look in into what's going on and
understand deeply what what happened,
right? And one of the things I found is
this is kind of antiattern that I saw uh
antipattern 14. So perfect recall
policy. So the idea is that basically
people think that because AI read the
whole internet, it remembers the whole
internet and it's a bug that it doesn't
know the details of your library
specifically. And I think that's a not
that's not right. Uh so here's an
example. So I was coding with a friend.
She's a chess coach and regular
chessboard looks something like this,
right? That's the initial setup. But she
wanted special special setup because she
teaches kids chess and she makes them
like chase each other's pieces all the
board. Kings are not important in this
context. So [clears throat]
we are kind of starting this project and
we created the board and now like okay
let's wipe the board and let her set up
the pieces and like kind kind of vibing
this one a bit together. Not quite but
like close to that and all right so
kings are not important right so
AI got stuck and when I looked into why
uh there was something that wasn't I
didn't expect which is uh apparent so so
we were testing from the UI and we were
like AI got stuck we asked it to do a
thing it's like yeah it's done no no um
so I stopped it and said hey go and
write write yourself some code with this
chessjs library that you're using,
right? Play with it. And when it did, it
went in and understood what is
happening. It's like, oh, I'm just I
just writing this test to put the the
chess pieces. I'm running into this.
This is what the problem is. So, the
chess GS basically requires kings to be
present on the board. And that wasn't
obvious and that wasn't clear. So, like
one would might expect AI to know the
details of chessjs, but I I argue that
we shouldn't. So what you can do instead
what I showed you just now is play is a
pattern number 15 playgrounds you can
basically allow it to go and write like
whenever you you're experiencing a new
library um or you're stuck with because
of new library make make it a little
playground and let it play there write
yourself some code and then you can
extract knowledge from that and have a
document of how to use this library
properly you can also point to documents
obviously right so I have in cloud MD
basically this idea of I have throwaway
explorer code. I allow you to go and
explore when you need to. So when you
run into a problem you didn't expect,
write yourself some exploratory code
piece to see what's going on. Use
playgrounds folder in the project and
create create it if it doesn't exist and
make sure it's in g ignore. I I find it
uses it quite a lot and it helps to get
itself unstuck and because it's
temporary, I treat it as delete
everything because I don't like noise.
So it helps. So basically don't expect
to know details. Give it references.
Give give it information. Right? That
expectation is just not something that's
working. So don't don't hold on to it.
You can ask it to search and when you
experiment you can extract knowledge
from that into reference docs and next
time it won't get stuck. Right? Next
time for example I have UV like I use UV
a lot. So I have a tiny document about
UV. Here's how to use UV. Now let's do
Python. Right? Now I'm get silliness
again after experiencing it once. So
that leads us to antipattern number 16.
unvalidated leaps. So the idea is this
basically long time ago when I was a
young developer just starting I peered
with somebody who blew my mind uh
because of the way she worked. So we
coded for three hours and we didn't run
the code once and the thing that was
growing through my brain was uh wait I
see this thing here but you're making
assumption that that call returns a
string. Do you know that? And then this
other thing like there's another
assumption and so so I was not surprised
when we ran this and it didn't run at
all. So it felt like we're hitting the
wall immediately. Right? So first of all
we needed to do compiling then the next
line didn't work. It was pretty
horrible. Uh thing is like this is what
you get as a human when you write a
piece of code without testing kind of
guaranteed to happen for the most part.
Um AI does the same thing. So but
somebody but people pretty much expected
to just get things right. But when it
gets stuck. So basically the idea is
this. You have a series of steps. You
got blocked on step D. So something is
not working and you ask to debug and it
checks here, checks there, maybe even
checks there. But and the problem is
actually in wrong assumptions about
something that step a returns, but it
didn't check that, right? So what you
can do is basically slow it down and
validate each step. That helps a lot.
And another thing that's just magical
and you should probably do it everywhere
is pred TDD in general because it forces
those little little feedback loops,
right? And predicting TDD is especially
a thing I like a lot. So learned it from
Ted Young. The idea is simple. So
whenever you start coding, you basically
predict um okay, I'm going to run the
test and the code doesn't exist. So it's
going to fail because the code doesn't
exist. Okay, now I wrote some code. it's
going to fail because or it's going to
it's going to compile and be okay
because I'm returning this one and I'm
testing the one and so on. So what it
gets you actually is you get surprised
when what you get is not that and that
kind of like constant checks of your
mental model across like against reality
and the AI gets the same the same
reaction as well which I found helpful.
So I really like that. I use it a lot.
So the way I got to it is like I
actually kind of sat with it and did
that together and then I extracted
knowledge and I have a predictive TDD
file now. So I can use it immediately
everywhere.
Another problem is AI struggles under
complexity. So
uh whenever the projects start more
complicated one way of managing
complexity is this chain of small steps.
So that's part number 17 and the idea is
pretty simple. So again you have you
have to manage complexity right? some
something needs to manage complexity. If
a doesn't you kind of got it. Um that's
not the only way to work but this one
definitely works. So here's an example.
So again from hack for good. So we were
doing um we were doing an application in
hack for good um and we started with
version one and by the end of three days
we had version 51. So we released a lot
and we immediat like we kind of found
that we need this version thingy that
I'm showing in the red. um kind of very
quickly because when we started like
pushing the the code it when it wasn't
working we're like okay is it the old
version or it doesn't work right so we
need a version so let me show you how we
added the version and again this is a
very simple example but it gives you the
idea of how you can do it in more
complicated things the one thing we
didn't do is we didn't go like show the
version number in the config and always
increment it when we make a new feature
because that would be violating of load
deterministic right AI is not good at
incrementing things reliably so don't
ask it
So what I do instead is I do this in
three steps. So this is chain of steps,
right? Step number one, very simple. We
have a we don't have a version number.
We'd like a version number. It I'd like
it to show in the UI. Let's make a
hardcoded one and make it show. Deadly
simple. It does it. That's step number
one. Now we have a version that is just
hardcoded to to something and it's a
variable. Okay. Then create me a thing
that updates that, right? So you update
the version. create me updated Sage. The
only thing it does when it runs is off
up offset variable one. Again, deadly
simple.
So now you have a thing. You created a
new thing. Very easy to create new
things. Cost of new things is zero. So
and and then you you don't want to do
this automatically. You don't want to
remember this. So you ask, hey,
implement a githook to do that, right?
And implements the githook, gets stuck
in the middle again, I think, but it
figures it out pretty quickly. And now
you have a gith hook. So you kind of
took three steps. Um so you have a
version number, you have a thing that
ups it and a git hook, right? But like
there's actually several small patterns
here. So there's a chains of small steps
I just showed you offload deterministic.
We didn't use AI for things that AI is
not good at. And we focus the agent,
right? We only were doing one thing at a
time. And then there's a knowledge
checkpoint. Uh we cannot we can't save
it. I don't I don't necessarily know
that I actually do that here, but you
can also save it here in the middle,
right? Um, another problem with with AIS
that you encounter is kind of selective
hearing. So, when you tell it things in
the ground rules, it's like do this or
don't do that. Um, it starts ignoring it
and there's there's several reasons for
that. So, right, you you strip down
ground rules to the core. You narrow the
scope, but some rules are still not
being followed. I found there's at least
two different types of things that are
happening and it's good to know what's
going on specifically. So first of all
you're going against agent training
and another thing is you the agent is
just getting too much stuff and getting
distracted the agent training one. So
one example is like if you actually try
to make your AI not commit code you know
how how much of a lost battle that is.
>> Yeah nervous laughter I know. Uh, and so
interestingly, Claude MD like if you
look at the entropic like system prompt,
you know what you find there? Don't
comment code. [sighs and gasps]
It settles all the way down. Doesn't
work. So, you can't outprompt this
stuff. Why? Because you're dealing with
something that's so ingrained in the
training data that outprompting is just
it just ignores it because like it's
overloaded with this statistical noise
of the training data, right? And I
especially saw it in this whisper. So
this is what whisper model. This is a
voice model that allows you to talk to
um so basically it's speech to text. So
you talk to to something it translates
it to text and it was interesting
because like I started working with it
directly in my application and um this
so there's silences there conversation
have silences. I'm trying to make an app
that transcribes the way I speak and
does things with it. But I have to deal
with silences. And this model actually
hallucinates things on silences. And the
things that's hallucinates is like like
it was trained on mostly the whole
YouTube and what every YouTube video
has. Please like or subscribe. Right? So
this is what you get on silences and
like prompting it out is fun. I tried
it. So you can basically like hey
there's no applause going on. This is
not a YouTube video, different context
entirely, but it still kind of
hallucinates that stuff. So, what you do
is basically pull out a big gun and just
force it. And I'll show you in a second
how to do it. So, you basically just let
it do it. It's a it's a lost battle.
Don't even try to outprompt it. So,
automate taking it out, right? And we'll
get to that. And then when getting the
getting distracted is is just focus it.
So, it's another pattern. We'll get to
it in a second. Uh, so, okay, agent
training. So what you do the force,
right? How do you use force? So hooks
are amazing. They're in claude code. I
know that. I don't know if they're in
different things, but I'm going to show
them anyway because I think they're
going to be everywhere or they must be
everywhere because they're amazing. And
the beauty of hooks is so uh basically
you you're dealing with the agent. This
thing on the left is the agent, right?
The only nondeterministic part is this
part, but this part is code. Pretty much
code, right? So there's rest calls to a
nonistic agent. And when you talk to it,
you kind of you kind of talk to this
agent, but you can hook into different
parts of this process, right? So when
you pull up the window, that's a thing
you can hook into new conversation is
started, right? So they have an event
for this and and that code is
deterministic which is wonderful because
the thing you can do and you can do like
when you edit use this edit tool do that
and this is custom script you can run in
those events, right? So what I do this
with this for example is I take away
comments, right? So yes, I still try to
be like don't comment my code, but
here's an example of me messing up with
my agent. So I already have this hook in
and it already knows how to detect
comments um for specific files. Uh and
when so I'm I'm like hey agent can you
add a comment please comment this file
over here that is it's a baby file so
it's fine. So it adds a comment and the
comment is as helpful as they usually
are. So okay, hello world. This is a
hello world. Thanks. And clot clot basic
clot code screams at it, right? So what
what you get is on the edit I ran my
script. So it ran my script for me
because of the edit tool was used. It
saw the comment screamed at agent and
agent is like, "Oh, oh, sorry, sorry.
Okay, I'll take it out, I guess." Right?
Very helpful. This actually reliably
keeps comments out of my code. I like it
and you can do so much more things with
it. Visibility stuff you can do and and
so many so reliability as well because
you can you can also actually enforce
quality that Ordog does a lot of that. I
think she was presenting earlier
somewhere on the on uh yeah in in this
um community. All right. So that's like
when things are really bad but also like
agents might get distracted. So if it's
a distracted agent and you don't want to
start a new context, I'm kind of often
in that situation. The the thing you can
do is remind it, right? Remind of the
important things and that's annoying. So
there's different ways to do this, but
actually that helps a lot. So first
thing is is to-dos. To-dos are amazing.
Uh it's a difference between here's a
thing 10 things and I'll just tell you
to buy right in the grocery store or
here's a list. Kind of does the same
thing for the agent. it can look and
kind of follow it kind of is like
focusing it on one thing at a time. So
all the tools all the coding tools are
using that and instruction sandwich is
just taking the idea of to-dos to the
next level. So the way it looks like is
this. So,
okay. So, I have this. So, this is a
to-do list, a big one. It's a
refactoring. I'm refactoring something.
And you see the blue lines are basically
I I want whenever I refactor, I want it
to run tests, do stuff, and then run
tests. If I just tell it run tests every
time you do it, it probably won't work.
But this actually makes it much more
reliable. Like 90%ish,
95%ish more reliable. So, this is
instruction sandwich, right?
um kind of I'm like, hey, important
thing I care about putting in the to-do
as one step and it's much less likely to
miss it. Here again, another test
sandwich, right? All right. You can also
automate that. So with hooks, I actually
automated this for claude and this is
something like that's a tiny little
library. It's dead simple. And that's
the only thing that actually makes so
what it does is every time it the AI
does it any or I prompt it shows it one
of those reminders and the reminders are
like the most important things in life
for me and it's invisible to me. So
actually I got this idea from from
actually Andropic because I I found out
I was super intrigued about why to-do
lists why it's so good at doing to-do
lists and the and why is because
Entropic actually screams at it under
the hood quite a lot. there's a lot of
system problems that they're doing to
like like hey your tool is kind of like
your to-do list is kind of small did
like maybe you should put something
there and that makes a difference so I
kind of do the same thing there's a cost
to it and the cost is context right this
is like where you value this is why only
five things go here for me right so all
right so we talked about nondeterminism
and how you can kind of exploit or
protect against it and then the idea of
people having that people have about AI
has to remember everything that's Not
true, right? It doesn't like it would be
nice but no. And hallucinations often
like some other things in disguise. Um
so you can use playgrounds basically let
AI explore extract documentation and
like use the extracted documentation as
references so next time it's not blocked
and then unvalidated lips. Um yeah AI
does that. You can kind of stop and slow
it down a bit. Uh you have to manage
complexity. nothing it it doesn't like
that's probably the biggest problem with
it. It doesn't manage complexity by
default. So something needs to one of
the ways to do it is this. Another way
is actually the way I do it a lot is I
let it run free for a while and then I
refactor together with it and that
brings some goodness.
Uh and then selective hearing, right? So
there's some commands that are so
stubborn and so annoying that you can
you either can just you have to kind of
force it or you can kind of nag it if if
you want to. And then that gets us to
last pattern in this antiattern in this
bit. So AI slop. So AI produces really
bad code
and slop and it's everywhere. It's
horrible. I hate it. Right. So what do
we do? Um well AI slop recipe is very
simple. You prompt AI. You may be
lightly edit but that's optional and
then you just present it as your work.
Zero thought, care anything put in it.
Zero value. Please don't do it. Um so
and common spaces become useless. People
leave the badness in shoes. Right? So um
so we can't stop other people obviously
but at least we cannot add to it. Uh but
what does it look in code right? So kind
of no non guardrails web coding and it
has a place. So V coding has a place.
It's fine, but like don't do it in
production and be careful, right? I I
actually think that some people that
don't VIP code small tool when they need
a small tool that won't change are kind
of like wasting their time a bit, right?
Um
but it's a it's it requires so much good
judgment. It it's it's like requires
time and judgment, I think, like nothing
else I saw before. But a thing that's
crucial to this is like don't expect
single pass to produce good code because
people t tend to do that and I think
that's wrong.
I don't see AI producing good code and
the best past ever. So what do you do?
So first thing somebody pointed out that
it wasn't my first talk and it has to be
I use this a lot. So what you can do
first to improve the quality of the
first pass dramatically is flip it. So
the first variation of this is this. So
you have a coding agent on the on the
left that's a coder. You open another
one on the right and its job is to
review. First coder codes. So you give
it a task in a file would be lovely
because you can point the other one to
it as well and you say hey implement it.
Cool. Now you have a diff in your you
you can commit it or you can just keep
it up out and you go to reviewer and say
hey here's the task the original file or
the original thing I asked the other
thing to do. here's the code for it. Can
you please suggest improvements
and it does and then the coder goes and
applies improvements. Dramatic
difference like the difference it makes
is a lot and that's good to do before
human review because if you don't do
this like it just takes so much effort
to to manage noise. So AI can actually
take a lot of this noise out. And then
the second variation that is interesting
is one agent. So you just have a coder.
You ask a coder to to do a task. Then
you give it a task and you're like,
"Hey, look at what you just did. This is
what we're trying to do. Can you find
problems with what you did and suggest
improvements?" And then you apply
improvements. So interesting thing is
that works and it works amazingly. And
I'm not convinced that the other thing
works better.
Um so question is why? I don't know, but
it's fascinating and I think it's very
interesting because it tells us things
about what are we dealing with. So I
have a theory. I think it only has focus
enough to only focus on one thing as
complexity grows as you ask it to do
more. So when it codes it looks at
different things, right? So I think and
and that kind of comes at cost of
everything else. So all the things you
said about hey don't comment my code or
complexity all the stuff gets ignored.
It's so rushing towards its goal it just
zooms out of that ignores it. So when I
refocus it, I think the I give it a new
main task. It becomes its male goal and
it's really good at one task doing one
thing it's really good at and it can
notice things. So people are saying AI
doesn't know how to write good code but
if you ask it you it always it often
tells you pretty decent things and it
can detect badness. It can detect
hardcoded variables and all other
things. So this is one of the ways. So
this is a very simple one but the
question is can we do better? This is
nice right? So the next pattern is 22
refinement loop.
So can we do better? So single pass we
saw how single pass usually produces
poor results and even adding one
feedback loop actually produces
dramatically different and better code.
What if we generalize and loop
right so I started doing this a lot and
I love it and this is an example of like
what so this is an example of a process
file. I'm just starting with this. Um so
Llewellyn has this really amazing
process file. Uh this is a refactoring
process. Whenever you have a code like
say you have a file you give it this
process file and you say hey follow this
process to improve this code. I hope you
have tests. Tests are helpful a lot
[gasps] guarantees that it not
guarantees but goes a long way towards
not breaking things. Right? So
uh this process is for refactoring
production code. It's in the link so you
can also yeah you can also see it in the
resources and then so I gave it a goal
so it's a refactoring process then I
chose um to to do one simple refactoring
so ah okay so we have a goal refactoring
then first of all ensure all the tests
pass then do the simplest thing you can
think of to improve this code and then
run the test notice instruction sandwich
run the test run the test right and then
we are taking one one simple simple step
towards a goal and the fact that it's
the simplest one I think is very
important uh and then we commit each
thing and it's also important because it
makes it iterative because if you say
hey go refactor this code the output of
it doing it on one go will be
dramatically different and worse is what
I noticed and why I think this little
small like choose the smallest thing you
can do to improve I think what we're
dealing is what I see in practice a lot
is uh there's a lot of noise that's in
your face and it's really hard to see
things behind this noise. You cannot see
deeper until you get rid of noise or
badness, right? So you you fix the
immediate problems, hardcoded things.
You make the file small and now you can
think about think deeper and so on. And
it kind of works for AI as well, right?
So we have an idea of refinement loop. I
started in doing this a lot. There's a
few variations and here's the recipe. So
first of all, you define your goal like
here's what we're trying to do and the
things this can be many things. So you
can be refactor this code or improve the
quality or simplify
um or I often do this get to the gist of
what this code is meant to be and meant
to do that's I'm trying to do this in
the fact that's interesting
um don't have the ready thing yet but
yeah and then AI makes one pass towards
the goal right so only take one step
choose the simplest one I recommend save
the immediate steps to follow command
this is crucial Because if you don't do
this, it will just pretend that it like
iterated and it won't iterate and the
the difference will be dramatic. So
either commit after every attempt or put
it in into a file and be like hey create
file number one now number two look at
the file number one let's iterate out
the goal and basically that enforces
iteration and then basically repeat
until AI sees nothing and to improve and
then you look as a human. So you use AI
to get a a lot of badness out before you
get to review and that kind of saves a
little bit of mental space for
developers because yeah it produces a
lot of code. It's hard to keep the
quality up. All right. So we're dealing
with something nondeterministic um and
there's ways to handle that. Uh there's
idea of hallucinations um that are not
really a problem and you can put things
into like you can let AI experiment. Um
there's unvalidated leaps that everybody
makes including AI and you can kind of
slow it down. Um AI degrades under
complexity. Somebody needs to manage it.
This is one way to do that. And then
this concept of selective hearing like
you tell things it's still not following
instructions, tricky instructions. So
there's hooks and reminders to deal with
that. And then the concept of AI slop.
So AI produces bad stuff. There's some
things you can do with this. There's
definitely more and we need more, right?
We need much more than this but like we
I think we're all figuring it out. So
feedback flip is a big quick way to
improve the results dramatically and
refinement loop is amazing. Try it. I I
I just do it everywhere now and it's
really really powerful. All right. So
that got us to the next uh pit stop. I
think we'll have time for questions. Do
you want some? Yeah. Go ahead.
Uh, thank you. Um, so how do you balance
that refinement loop
kind of steering or guidance that you're
giving the agent with sort of does that
go into your general list or is that
like a coding sort of instruction set
you keep?
>> I usually open a new window.
>> Okay.
>> And so I started doing this things. So
I'm exploring how to refactor with AI a
lot.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So the thing I was I started
doing is like I have a little um a
little file where I store the
instructions of how to get to the gist
of the gist of the code. What the code
is does. I'm trying to get to super good
English.
>> Mhm.
>> Right. Explain the intent of this code
because this is step number two in my
like thing I'm trying to do with
refactoring like Lance thing is step
number one. This is step number two. But
I need to get to the gist
>> and then from gist I kind of be like now
apply to code. So like I flip it off.
So, but that's the idea. Did I answer
your question or did
>> Yeah. So, you I must have missed that
you use this flow really specifically
for that. Not for
>> No, no, no. Like all kinds of stuff,
right? So, if I if so I sometimes think
with it, right? So, I'm like, I need a
better solution than this stuff.
>> How do I do this? And I put it into a
file or I can just prompt it and be
like, hey, I want you to think this way.
So, you probably want a slash command,
something like a little slash command.
This is the goal. We are trying to get
to it. Here's the process. follow like
put save things in the file reflect on
it given the goal try and to improve
until you see no things to improve
that's that's what I would do thanks for
re asking I get distracted sometimes
thanks
>> hey
okay uh so given these steps to refactor
and refine the code so what's the best
way to have multiple people in a team
follow the similar practice so everyone
is not defining their own way of doing
it
>> I don't know that I have rules for
multiple people because I think it's
going to be depend and on the team,
right? And the like more programming
with AI is a general thing people are
trying to figure out because kind of
feels weird. You mostly just stare at it
working have a lot of time to talk or
you work on three projects like mad like
like I do sometimes. [gasps]
Yeah. So I'm I'm not sure I'm not sure I
have an answer for this. I'm sorry. I
wish I did.
I think the eventuality like let's say
we master all of those techniques
everything in here is is cranking right
eventually
this is far less interactive and maybe
far more like batch work maybe you start
in the morning you do an hour worth of
hammering stuff out it goes off into the
ether generates your stuff and come back
after lunch it's sort of that kind of
I'm thinking how we're going to work as
teams together Right. Um, one person
this is possible. You go to the second
person, it all falls down.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think we're all figuring it out
still.
>> Well, there's a bunch of projects trying
to do it. Would it like
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, have you seen any of the
projects that attempt to aggregate these
learnings? There are there are several.
>> Yeah. Which do you know?
>> So, spec ones.
>> There's also multi agent ultimately in
the background. It's just like
subjective. It's just taste really like
they're all implementing the same kind
of treadmill of stuff.
>> So if you have interesting links also
share them in the Discord so other
people can pick them up and kind of
stay. I know there's a lot of questions.
I'm going around the room so please be
patient. We do have some time. So
>> thanks Patrick.
>> Um question in in your process here
which is really good by the way. Great
talk. um where where do you stand with
the use of sub aents as they start to
emerge and how do you pass tasks between
context or pass the right information to
the sub aent and think it goes into the
story and maybe it's in your next step
but I I I [snorts] feel there's an
opportunity there. I'm just wondering
what you think about how you use them.
>> I wanted to love them so so badly. I
don't include code because they take
away the context. So they have the same
problem as MCPs, right? Plus
nondeterministic fact like it it it
launches them nondeterministically.
Is my microphone up? Can you hear me?
Okay, cool, cool, cool. So um so I was
kind of on hack for good at the time and
they launched the agents. I'm like, "Oh
my god, I want to come back and play
with agents." All I can think of. But um
so I started playing with agents and so
I I made my committer into an agent. It
didn't run it reliably. Plus you you can
start seeing like you can do the look at
what is my contact. same problem as an
MCP, right?
>> Uh yeah, usage. Yeah. So it pollutes
your context and I I care. You see how
much I care about my context and I have
a good reason to. I showed you the
committer, right? So I care about my
context most of I don't use agents. I
think I'm convinced that I need to try
it out myself. That the key to like the
goodness is probably small small focused
things that only do one thing at a time,
but they need to be orchestrated
somehow. And that's tricky. I tried to
do this but uh like it's it's hard. So I
think the way clo claude code
implemented is not not good because of
that and also because of
nondeterministic parts. So I kind of I
don't I don't think helpful. I often
just open two seriously like I often
open two two close at the same time and
just have them either have them talk
because I wrote a little thing that
allows them to talk directly. Um and uh
you can also just have them like paste
things inside here and there. Yeah.
>> That also doesn't help you.
>> Yeah. Exactly. A lot because like you
can put context out, right? I had three
of them and like one was keeping keeping
the context of the whole thing. Another
implementing implementing is actually a
lot of details and that takes a lot of
context and just offloading to another
agent helps a lot but like you need to
figure out yeah I have thoughts about it
but like don't don't use agents I I want
to use them but I didn't find a good
way. I know there's cloud flow, right?
And I kind of tried it and I I kind of
want to go to that talk about cloud flow
because I tried it on I have a baby
project that I tried it every like so
ricochet robot, right? And I tried the
code flow there and it did like worse on
everything. So maybe I did it wrong.
>> I think I think let's two more. Um we'll
run what happens if we run out of time.
>> Okay. Yeah, that's fine. Let's do let's
do two questions and then and then
continue and at the end if you have time
we'll ask answer ask answer ask answer
ask answer ask answer ask answer ask
answer ask answer ask answer ask answer
ask questions.
>> So a common hallucination that we've
seen is if the unit tests are failing it
will just delete the unit test. Oh yeah.
>> Um would that be uh something that you
would solve with hooks and [snorts]
>> Yeah. Abs. I think so. I think so. Yeah.
You need to do something about Yeah.
It's so human too. Like I hate this
>> like cuz I I got burnt very easily early
on. I was like oh this test is wrong.
Sure. And I was doing doing dealing with
a multi threading and then it happened
in production the same thing that the
tester produced. And I one would learn
maybe normally from that but I didn't.
So I did it again and it has the same
results. So now I'm like super careful.
I'm like no no no no tests triple sure
like no deleting tests think and so on.
You still have refactoring but like so
many people are just like delete tests
and agents do the same thing.
Absolutely. Hooks I think. Yeah that's
the way to go.
>> Just for reference has a feature where
you can say this files cannot be touched
by AI. So it's like almost like access
control by saying you allow it to do.
Okay. Next question.
>> Okay. Thank you. So I see um two main
directions here. Um and I see that
there's a we need a trade-off between
the convergence towards small steps and
as deterministic as possible to maintain
right the u the undeterministic aspect
of that. But then there is the
flexibility of allowing AI to do the
best planner possible of what the ask
the initial ask is for.
>> Yeah. So my question and we have the
parallelism right. So my question is uh
do you have a best practices on do you
go in those parallel sessions down to
the small test? Do you want to how do
you iterate over them uh and marry the
small task level with the parallelis to
get rid of
>> yeah I would treat them as throwaways.
So like this is like running the dice
and the value is like it's so cheap
right? If you if you're doing what you
said I think it makes it expensive. So
that value goes down dramatically. So I
wouldn't do that. So I wouldn't manage
it. Right? So this is like um this is
where I think a lot of judgment comes
into play. And if you're doing things in
production, you probably want to do
super slow steps and like please be reli
like we don't want planes falling from
the sky. Badness. No, let's not do that.
Careful, right? But like if you're doing
something like I see also the other side
where people are not not not doing
throwaway things, not by coding small
tools and so on. And I think they're
missing out a lot because that hack for
good three days people coming in they
thought we wouldn't deliver anything and
that's [clears throat] what said we
won't deliver anything in three days
we've solved two of the problem and the
godm funding not because of wipe coding
but if we didn't wipe code we wouldn't
have time to focus on the important
stuff so I see both parts does it
>> yeah treat them as as as disposable
I I would because if you otherwise the
value goes down.
>> So it's it depends basically.
>> Okay, we can continue. Just one plug.
The tool she mentioned cloud flow will
be also part of a session later here
today. So if you want to explore that
tool, you know, feel free to come to
Dagger's talk as well. So please
continue.
>> What you said about tests outside, I
think it's fascinating. I think it's
necessary to have tests outside where
the AI doesn't hold tests because I
trust my AI with tests even less I trust
it with code
>> because it uses mock everywhere and I
yeah anyway all right so let's go to the
last step and so I think this is an
interesting bit that you kind of need to
understand and uh it really helps when
you have ways to fight this so there's
two things that are kind of you need to
know about AI that come into place
together and together they're just
becoming deadly. Uh so first of all the
you're dealing something that's a black
box right you don't know what's inside
with code I can just pull it up and be
like oh okay I understand what does
don't have the luxury with AI so as a
result there's a chance of misalignment
between so unfortunately that thing has
a likeness of mental model I don'tize it
but like it's the closest thing you know
quarks like a duck um so and the
misalignments there are kind of very
hard to detect and even notice
So uh another thing that comes into play
that amplifies that is this thing have
been trained with a bias put in place
deliberately to be obedient to you and
oftentimes suddenly obedient. So like
it'll ask you most it'll do most things
you ask it and silently right and will
not ask questions. So uh basically we
have a blackbox AI with compliance bias
and what it leads to is antipattern
number 23 silent misalignment. So like
when I saw this that was interesting. So
here me this is me like the version
version first of my application. I'm
this is a a way to fill in the forms
with voice aentic thing. Um
straightforward I did the back the back
end for it got it right. Okay. And now
I'm like, "Okay, this front end makes me
annoyed because this top part, I meant
it to be the same size and it didn't do
it this way. I totally now it's the time
to fix it." Okay, so I go to like, "Hey,
fix it, please." And it goes and does
it. And to me, like this is clear,
right? So I'm talking about this two two
panels on the left panel and the right
panel. They have top parts and the
bottom parts. Straightforward. Like the
header kind of is a good view of where
one part ends. So I go to AI, I'm like,
"Hey, please make them level the same
size, please." It goes like, "Sure, here
you go. It's done." I look at it and
it's not done. I'm like, "Okay, it's not
done. Here's a screenshot. Please fix
it." It goes and does it again. It was
like five iterations of that. And then I
started suspect something. So when I go
is like, "Hey friend, can you like when
I say top parts and the bottom top
parts, can we like color them in
background in different colors, please?"
And I see this
and so you can see that it has red
things, right? So it has these two parts
and it thinks that microphones is
doesn't belong here and it totally does.
And then it thinks that incident report
form belongs to this header. So no one
it was doing some random stuff when I
was talking to it like okay so I was
telling it things and not making any
sense in its universe and the next
question I have here is why on earth
didn't it ask me a simple question what
do you mean
right and this is what made me think
about this and um so first of all really
hard to even detect right so I didn't
expect it to not know things it did this
silently so it wasn't doesn't make any
sense and it didn't ask questions. So
this made me think that I need to do
something about it. Right? So this leads
to pattern number 24 active partner. So
I have ground rules where I have
proactivity rules and the productivity.
So so I showed you the Elizabeth
Hendrickson one, right? Tell me
something I need to know even if I don't
want to hear it. But there's more
things. So push back on something seems
wrong. Don't just agree with mistakes is
in my ground rules.
um ask questions if something is not
clear and you need to make a choice.
Don't choose randomly. And I also
prompted and prompted
uh and then when you show me a potential
error miss please start your reply with
an emoji and now I know that this rule
hit which is nice. Uh so the way I
enforce this partnership is twofold.
First of all global rules so um they
have several things. So ground rules
have first of all honest feedback is
there. Permission to disagree is there.
you have to actively give it permission
to disagree and kind of probably enforce
it in impromptu as well and then
practically point out mistakes. I find
it really helps. And then impromptu
prompting oftentimes I'm like, what do
you think? Give me the honest feedback,
right? Or do you have any questions?
This is something I do all the time
before I implement anything. And that
saves me a lot of energy because I'll
show you the next pattern. Um, like it's
proactively taking care of future
problems. So, do you have any questions?
And notice how I don't say, "Do you have
three questions?"
Because I I see so many people saying,
"Oh, give me five questions." Like, why
do you do this to yourself? Like first
of all, h how do you know how many it
had? If you forced it to three, what if
it had five and the fi fifth was was the
most crucial one you had to know? You
ask you you limited it to something
unnecessarily or you said three but it
only had one. Now you just mix up
questions because you asked for three.
Sure, you're wasting your time. Why?
Don't do this to yourself. I don't think
it's helpful. So, and then the thing I
ask similar to questions is everything
clear, right? Every time before I start
actually creating something, right? And
I find that that it often says no not
this is not clear let's talk about this
and now I kind of figure it out
immediately. So this is what I was just
talking about. So top pattern number 25
check alignment right? So the idea is
simple like I described you you do a
request the so you talk to it AI goes
implements and say it fails right
because it misunderstood on this request
step. So and you wasted two time 20
minutes just like it implementing if it
was a big feature. uh I mean it's less
important that your time explaining to
it and potentially you saved it to
acknowledge point so you're fine right
but still a time of your life you waited
for it so basically what I do is like
introduce a step in between right so
show me your show me what the
architecture your understanding of
architecture usually often asky and then
what do you plan to change in succinctly
right and then helps me notice nonsense
quickly uh and then if if I catch
misunderstanding early it goes and
implements and maybe it fails But it
doesn't fail for the this reason of
misunderstanding.
Um yeah, so basically we have a very
obedient silent box and very mysterious
and that leads to silent misalignment.
It's really hard to see what's inside
and the detecting and even suspecting
sometimes is hard, right? So you kind of
have to fight it actively and one way to
do this is like proactively give it
permissions and liberties to do things
and also prompt impromptu ask questions.
That helps a lot. And then you can check
alignment like, hey, do you understand
me? Show me what you're about to do
before you do that. Save saves your
time. And so I'm going to show you the
context markers. This is something I
encountered in the form of uh somebody
was like, "Hey, call me xname when you
talk to me." Right? That's nice, but
like and they usually use silly names.
And it was funny for the first three
messages, but got old very quickly. And
also it takes tokens. So I started doing
emojis and I really like this. Uh the
idea is simple. So whenever you put an
instruction or whenever you kind of ask
it to do something or even ground rules.
Here's my ground rules. So I have code
MD and I have the first rule I have
there is always start applies with
started character plus space and the
default character character is this
clover thing and also allow it to suck.
So the idea is simple. Uh when I talk to
my claude I open the window and the
first thing I see when I ask the
question is this. So this cl is always
there and this is information to me.
information is it read my ground rules,
right? And especially in wind surf when
I saw this thing going away, I'm like,
okay, now the context is really really
big. It forgot everything I cared about.
Like, no, I need to restart, right? Kind
of makes this invisible bit visible. It
read my ground rules. But that's not not
the only thing you care about. And
that's why I think emojis are better
because they're also super noticeable
and you can stack them. So, here's how I
stack them. I have my committer and the
committer has a special emoji and I say
add this to the starter emoji. So now
when I'm in committ mode, I see this and
it gives me two pieces of information.
It read my ground rules and also it is
following the process of a committer. It
knows how to inhibit. It remembers my
rules. Helpful. You can also do it in in
a place. So like you give it an
instruction and say hey add this emoji
and show me. Now I know that it
remembers the process files. So again
falos process files. If you haven't
watched this talk it's in my resources.
It's awesome. But the idea is basically
it's like a step-by-step it's it's like
a code piece in English. Um but I use I
use this a lot in there and I I like it
here. So the idea is like whenever you
switch to a process file so you give a
process file be like hey do TDD here and
I have three emojis in my TDD and it
shows me if I make green read green are
refactor stage and here for example this
is refactoring process just showing me
and now I know it's not just refactoring
because I asked it to refactor it's
actually following the process right so
this is just example of some of the
things I use you can do whatever you
prefer uh interestingly I had an
interesting conversation with yes like
yesterday or two days back. Um, so you
you can do this with text as well for as
a quick one, but it can be emoji as
well. But somebody was like, oh my cloud
MD is giant, so I'm going to just take
that map MD or pieces of it, put it into
a file and referring cloud MD to that
file. And I already kind of did that and
I already tested how it works. So I knew
to be like careful. I actually like do
you know that's actually because he was
like, oh, it's lazy loaded. I'm like, do
you know it's lazy loaded? How do you
test? Right. So um very simple I put I
go into that file and say Chewbacca when
you read this and I open a new file and
if you see Chewbacca it's not lazy
loaded simple right same idea
so okay so we're getting close to the
end but there's a few things to go still
through answer injection so antipattern
number 27 and this is really good to
know and also you can weaponize it which
is the pattern following this one so
Um, I'll show you a simple example and
then a non-simple example that shows why
it's so important. Simple example is
really that simple. I want to organize a
team celebration. I go to charge PT and
say, "Hey, which fancy restaurant should
I book?" And it will tell you which
fancy restaurant should you book. You
know what? It won't tell you that
there's this special deal and there's an
amazing show going on over there because
you didn't ask. So, you limited your
answer with your question. That's the
idea of answer injection. I I'm being
like cheeky with answer injection
because you know prompt injection but
the idea is simple right um so instead
if you ask it give me more suggestions
you get much more broader uh solution
space right so you brought like you're
limiting your solution space so but this
is sneaky this is very obvious one it
gets really sneaky because so let me
show you this so I had two clot codes
that was back in June and I just
switched to clot codes was absolutely uh
loving it because the difference between
windsurf was dramatic
and I had this left cloud code on the
left and the hooks didn't exist and I
was annoyed at it not following
instructions and I was figuring things
out. So I was like what if I have
another cloud code on the right that's
like a reminder it's like it's only job
is to tell it things. So I need them to
talk can I do this and it's kind of fun
project to to to think about and do
right so just a thing to to play with.
So, okay. So, I go and like, "Hey,
Claude, can you send a message to
another clot code? Can you please go and
research if you need to?" And goes and
researches and it's like, "No, no,
sorry. Cloud codes can't send messages
to each other." I'm like, "Okay,
well, okay. Well, maybe I can do other
things. I know that clot can launch uh
shell scripts, right? That's easy. Well,
you know, shell script or cloud, right?
It can't run another cloud. Can I open
it in a different window?" So I use that
term a lot. I term now I'm in ghostly
and ghosty. Um so I can open several
windows. Um and so I kind of figure out
how to do that. I write a little script
for that and it launches cloud code.
Lovely. Works. Launched. I see it in a
different terminal. Fantastic. And then
something happened by mistake. I think I
just pressed error up or something and
like hey launch clot code and it's like
that. So it went to this other terminal
on the right. Well, if you look at this,
it kind of looks like a message. The
only thing that needed to be different
for it to be launched is this cloud code
needed to not be launched, right? So I
just sent one message from window to
another. But wait, that means I can send
messages to another cloud code and I
just wasn't asking, right? So what I
asked originally was something along the
lines of can you send another message
like to message to another cloud code
research if you need to. And there's a
tiny tiny sneaky answer injection there.
And it actually may work. It's like it's
a it's a guess game. Will it work or
not? In this case, it didn't. It
actually interpreted it in a different
way. It said well it actually
interpreted as does cloud code have
support for sending messages to other
code and went to search and very
reasonably said no because it doesn't.
Right? But what I wasn't doing is I
wasn't describing what I was trying to
do broader. Right? Right? I wasn't
describing the problem extremely well.
And here I'm like now I went and said,
"Hey, I have two iter windows and I'm
trying to send messages from one to
another. How do I do this?" And it told
me and it taught me something new. It
taught me the concept of Apple script
that I wasn't familiar with before. It's
kind of funny thing. I tell that window
over there that this thing over there
needs to be launched. It's English kind
of craziness, but I didn't know it
existed. And now I wrote myself a little
tool that allows me to kind of have them
all talk to each other. So I can have
like them play with like do something
and actually work together. It requires
more management so I don't do this use
it very much but uh it's fun and I knew
I could use TMAX. I just didn't want to
use TMAX for reasons. All right. So the
so answer so that was answer injection
right this is why it's so bad.
Uh can I there's a a different thing
about this. So like you can take it to
11 by this is a small silly pattern.
Tell me a lie. Antipotent tell me a lie.
Right. This is a month ago with Jeminate
2.5. I'm like, "Hey, can you give me
five options of what 2 plus 2 is?" And
it kind of did. Sadly, it wasn't even
funny about it. So, at least when I when
I go to started 4.5, it first thing I
did, I was like, "Are you feeling all
right, human?" I'm like, "No, no, I'm
just messing with you. Just let's go
along with it. Just make me a joke or
something." And it actually make a funny
joke which makes it the first model that
actually made me laugh for for
deliberately. So that's nice, right? So
um yeah 2 plus two is five for extremely
large values of two. Nice. All right. So
I showed you the context. So we have a
silencing image here. You can see some
things make it something like visible by
using context markers. They're helpful
at places and good tool to have. There's
answer injection and tell me like like
this is limiting yourself. So don't
limit yourself with the way you ask the
question. Pay attention. But can you do
better
because we just saw that it taught me
something I didn't know. So right so AI
is extremely well read. It has amazing
amazing breath. It read the whole
internet. Doesn't necessarily remember
it but it knows like it's like you went
to a talk you don't remember everything
but now you kind of know that this thing
exists. So you know to look go look for
it right same thing and so so you don't
accidentally limit your eye but like can
we do better uh so
right this is an example of how you
could do better so this is hack for good
we were trying to do day two and we were
trying to
so we needed to solve a problem for them
of um we needed somebody to send state
to the state um information about uh the
program like some information about um
the usage of like the psychologist use a
tool. So we after end of the session we
need to send information to um a person
right and so so okay now we're figuring
out what's the architecture for this how
do we do this and they're extremely
limited oh my god they came to hackathon
and they're like we cannot deploy
anything because like money and uh and
government and and and lawyers are
getting involved and like we need at
least 40 bucks for 40,000 or something
for this. So, okay, this is my my my
friend was like, "Hey, okay, here's like
so he wrote a project file and he's
like, give me ideas of how to like we
have an email, right, an Outlook and we
need to get to emails from this outlook
for for spec with a specific header. How
do we do this?" And he's like, "Hey,
give me ideas." Uh, and the ideas can be
around, well, going an API, the server
itself, third party email client. Okay.
Well, do you know notice the answer
injection?
Yeah, he didn't. So, first of all, um
this is what we said on the right,
right? And this is what it gave us.
First of all, API options. Notice this
thing. API options, service operations,
servers, third party things. Third party
things. Notice what's not there.
Anything else, right? So only what we
asked for. So what do you what do you
do? So the thing I did there is like is
there a simple way? Because I always try
like I like simple. I keep I try to
force simple everywhere. Um things are
complex enough um without over
complicating them. So I do this and so
I'm kind of deliberately asking for it.
Um and here's it gave us an an answer
and the answer is very simple. You can
basically put it into a specific folder
and just do a simple script and that was
enough for this right. So it suggested
something else now because I was fishing
for it. So we kind of started
deliberately looking at your blind
spots. Basically you know that blind
spots are there. You know AI is well
read. So you can start to look at those
things. So think and the way I do this
is basically I plan a thing. I have a
draft plan. Now I want to poke holes in
it and like what solutions have we not
even considered? What am I not thinking
about? What is outside my universe
completely? Right. Can we make this
simpler is a big one. Um even simpler
than that I kind of push that often. And
then what entirely different approach
could work for this problem? Let's think
about abstractly and so on. Right? And
often times it gives me something that I
actually didn't even think about. And
you can you can basically allow it to
teach what you don't know. You don't
know. Right? So there's this. And we
have just a couple more patterns. I
think I'm going to run over a little
bit.
>> About 10 minutes.
>> I think that should work. Right. So
reverse direction is amazing part
pattern and I think it's my favorite one
at all and the idea is simple. Uh so
when you talk to AI you can think about
like you go to and like hey do this then
do that then do that thing over there
and do that thing more. So you kind of
like you can think about as a
conversation having inertia of you
you're getting into a habit of telling
it things and it takes commands and this
is how like things are maintained. What
I find very useful is reversing
direction. And the way you reverse
direction is often times like you can do
answer a question with a question. So
for example, here is like I want to do
something. What would you like to do?
Suggest me some things, right? So you
you you're prompting this out. Another
example of reverse diversion is actually
knowledge extracting knowledge. That's
also kind of you put knowledge in now
you're getting out the other way. But
here's an example of like here I wanted
to rename a file and the AI is like what
do you like to rename it to? And I don't
think here many people think here and
that's fine. uh but I don't think here I
ask hey give me some options and what
gives gives me is it gives me more
breaths and it gives me so I'm using
something that I know notice that is
like a human nature right when you see
something it often gives you more ideas
you didn't think of and also like if you
see something you want to change
something often times so this is where I
think you gave me a thing now I think
okay and now I poke and navigate it um
and I find it really useful um so when I
get yeah get more ideas and I can see
quickly see see what I like. It's
similar like you know how people are
sometimes like I like this idea let's
implement it this way no this way well
try all three and see what you like and
I think you won't have to argue
oftentimes wood does that a lot and I
think it helps all right so answer
injection is sneaky uh it's out to get
there so know that it's there but you
can also weaponize it so ask look for it
ask for it and reverse direction is
awesome so kind of treat treating your
AI as a something that can give you
things in immediately like in small
small iterations and the last two things
are super small. So this is about
modalities. So first of all this
polyglot AI and we're going to end with
an example that combines a few things
that I think will be interesting. So um
so use modalities right if you're not
using modalities first of all the main
modality is text and that's the main
language but there's also visions so you
can you can use images so give it images
with bugs and so on and you can also
generate images so many people are not
using this enough and I'll show how I'm
using it in the next step and for
generating like I so for example for
this presentation I use chat GPT and
nana banana and nana banana is amazing
because it does this so I generated the
pig and I'm like, "Hey, make this pig
smile." And notice how it's the same pig
that wasn't a thing four months back.
Wasn't possible, right? So, I like this
for presentations. Like, makes a lot of
difference. You can also make it grumpy
>> for reasons. And then uh so audio is
amazing. I don't know if you talk to
your AI. I talk to my AI uh a lot. I
could demonstrate, but the idea is
simple, right? So, audio to text. So,
there's amazing amazing tools. I like
super whisper. So and the idea is like I
put cursor anywhere and say hello uh
this is me speaking right um if you're
not using this this makes a lot of
difference AI can reply back to you so I
have ground rules about that and um it
can actually reply to me when it's and I
having ground rules basically hey when
you're done with a big step let me know
by voice or if you need to draw my
attention let me know so my commit is
like like hey lad there's some issues
some here or there need your attention
helpful,
right? And um so there's no way in hell
I would have typed this and the quality
of this is horrid. Like when you read
it, this like you're usually ashamed of
yourself, but that's like this is
something that it's it's fine. And AI
can make things sense of this. You can
also structure it. So blabber it then
have it structure it and then um like
have something meaningful out of this.
So, and then the fact that you're
talking to AI means that you have uh
flexibility in mistakes. So, when you
ask it, give me a dog and it transcribes
it as dog. It doesn't go and gives you a
dog, right? Which is nice. So, again, in
ground rules, I basically have this
using voice and the text native is the
last bit I think it's good to show. Uh
so, the idea is simple. Text is so so
powerful. Staying in text is magic. And
um I like to diagram an inki and I'm
gonna show you how I use it in this one
piece and I think we have like two
minutes on of this thing. So okay so
hack for good. We had an application
that was largely b coded like I said
mostly bip code not web code because we
care what's inside. We're just not
looking. Okay. Um and we have this page
and the page this is a counter and um
basically what it when I press email
results it goes to this page and when I
say yes it goes to this page and then or
model window and then it sends email
right so very simple flow we go and show
it to our product person and they're
like no no no no we can't do this so
this model windows can't can't exist
because you're asking yes no question
and that's self-reporting we care about
it you can't do this but if you ask it
in a sneaky way and still kind of
boolean out.
How many times did they do homework?
What was the score? Then we can actually
ask this question. So we so we need to
change the way the system works. But
it's white coded, right? So you kind I
kind of need to explain this AI a
complex system like idea. So my my
designer draws or product manager draws
things on the left. So this is this
window you see in front of you and on
the right there's the thing they want.
So this window, this summary is still
here, but we want on the right questions
and those questions are the ones I
showed you before. So the questions that
you want boolean out and this is the
questions here. So she she wrote this
out on on the sticky note and
so I can actually explain this to AI.
It's going to be a lot of work.
>> Can [clears throat] I can I take a big
step on simpler? So it's going to show
you several things. So first thing I'm
going to do it in several steps and I'm
going to use modalities here and I'm
going to stay at text. So first thing I
do is create a markdown document. So I
give it the two images and I say convert
this into ASKI for me. So I give this
image and this image is ASKI important.
Uh actually you may have like get away
without it but actually it allows me to
edit it as well which is nice. So and
this is what it does. So it produces
this result. So look at this summary
summary model model. Even this part is
here. This is pretty good, right? Uh and
then this part, the questions that's
captured very well. Format is wonky, but
that's fine. And then
uh so I don't need this part. I get rid
of that. So I kind of give it just that.
And I I kind of mess with it a bit,
right? To to get it to where I need to
be. So I get rid of the questions here.
They they didn't serve me. So questions
get out. And now what I do is here's an
image. I don't want to explain this
image to you, but you can understand it.
your eye, right? Go. And so I convert
image into text. I ask it, hey, describe
me an image, right? So we went from a
picture of a like an image that we had
to ask to text and it took me almost
zero effort. Right? So now I have a
thing. Now I kind of want to expand this
part. So I ask it to first rename it,
then fill it in with questions. Here's
the questions. And it does. And I kind
of it's kind of tiny and my product
person wants to me to edit this. So what
I do is I ask it to expand this and I
manually edit this because this is asky.
So I can in the same window grab this.
So this is my prompt. This is me giving
it and I just hugged it in very simple.
So
now I I ask to describe this window in
text. And now I have basically our goal.
And our goal is described in text,
right? This is the window. This is the
thing we want, the functionality we
want. Now, I want a to-do list. How do I
get to to-do list? There's an
application that already does things.
There's a future state. Go look at the
current state and show me what it does
right now. So, we created the markdown.
We're creating the to-do lists. And um
so, show me the current state. The
current state is this. This is roughly
what it's Yeah, this is a model window.
Then it goes to questions. Then it goes
to text. It's not perfect, but I kind of
feel that it gets what I what I mean
here. This is what I showed you before.
And now I'm like, okay, it it can go. So
So now we have the current state, right?
And now we can do the diff. We can do
the diff by here's a new state. Here's
an old state. Go look at the code. Make
a to-do plan list. How to get from state
A from state B, right? And um so we make
a plan. We created a to-do list and it
does. And the only thing that's left
here is make a change. And this is what
it produces immediately. And it works
just out of the box. So we state in
text. I stayed at text here like for a
long time and the aski prototyping here
allowed me to take minimal effort. This
is minimal effort to get to something.
So I I think this shows kind of
modalities and how powerful it could be
and some people are not using it to the
core. And I also have this is also like
chain of small steps, right? So we had
document then to do and then change the
code. So this is roughly what we're
dealing with. I'm I'm wrapping it up.
Sorry for being a bit over. Um I think
it helps to see the limitations and so
to just go through this really really
quickly. So AI can't learn. The only
thing you can do is reset and refill.
You're building its knowledge from
scratch. One way to do this is files,
right? Uh focus is scarce. Um and
context is not universal. So little
agents are really really powerful. And
uh text is elastic. That's a new power.
Use it to stay sane. You can zoom in and
out. and you can start using it
deliberately as a skill and it can
actually I find that it goes deeper than
the surface. um then same input is not
same input doesn't mean the same output
right non-deterministic but you can
design for it because you know it and
you can also protect yourself against it
or you can exploit and then don't expect
AI to just know things give it knowledge
or let it play with things extract
knowledge and use it and then this
tricky instructions they're very
stubborn there's ways to handle them
there's probably more ways to handle
them I don't this is not everything this
is just ground things I think right uh
So when don't expect awesome from one
pass. I think this is just a wrong
expectation. AI doesn't do that. U so
you can actually get to much much better
quality with refining. Um and we still
need better solutions for this. But
that's one of the ways. And then AI
mental model is hidden and it's trained
to say yes. So you can have you have to
actually actively fight that to get to
better results. Um plus there's breaths
that you can use that's a very strong
suit of it. And so don't accidentally
limit that breath. And also actively
push AI to teach you more, right? You
can actually weaponize that. And that's
getting the the best of things you can
get from AI. And then multimeodality is
this thing. It's amazing. And text is
really powerful. Stay in text. It's it's
just magic nowadays. This is the slides.
I think they're also in Discord. If you
if you forgot to do this, that's it. And
thank thank you for letting me run over.
[applause]
>> [music]
>> Heat. Heat. [music]